Guide to the Stanley Dance and Helen Oakley Dance Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Photographs
  - Earl Hines
    - 1960 (Box 46)
    - 1961 (Box 46)
    - 1962 (Box 46)
    - 1963 (Box 46)
    - 1964 (Box 46)
    - 1965 (Box 46)
    - 1966 (Box 46)
    - 1967 (Box 46)
    - 1968 (Box 46)
    - 1969 (Box 46)
    - 1970 (Box 47)
    - 1971 (Box 47)
    - 1972 (Box 47)
    - 1973 (Box 47)
    - 1974 (Box 47)
    - 1975 (Box 47)
    - 1976 (Box 47)
    - 1977 (Box 47)
    - 1978 (Box 47)
    - 1979 (Box 47)
    - 1980's (Box 47)
    - Hines with Muhammad Ali (Box 47)
    - Hines with Steve Allen (Box 47)
    - Hines with Jimmy Archey (Box 47)
    - Hines with Count Basie (Box 47)
    - Hines with Barney Bigard (Box 47)
    - Hines with Wallace Bishop (Box 47)
    - Hines with Eubie Blake (Box 47)
    - Hines with Teresa Brewer (Box 47)
    - Hines with Dave Brubeck (Box 47)
    - Hines with Benny Carter (Box 47)
    - Hines with Buck Clayton (Box 47)
    - Hines with Cozy Cole (Box 47)
    - Hines with Stanley Dance (Box 47)
    - Hines with Lois Deppe (Box 47)
    - Hines with Sweets Edison (Box 47)
    - Hines with Ralph Flanagan (Box 47)
    - Hines with Harlem Globetrotters (Box 48)
    - Hines with Haywood Henry (Box 48)
    - Hines with Hodges (Box 48)
    - Hines with Bud Johnson (Box 48)
    - Hines and Jonah Jones (Box 48)
    - Hines with Marva Josie (Box 48)
    - Hines with Billy Kyle (Box 48)
    - Hines with Joe Louis (Box 48)
    - Hines with Mezz Mezzrow (Box 48)
    - Hines with Shelly Moune (Box 48)
    - Hines with Charles Oden (Box 48)
    - Hines with Truck Parham (Box 48)
    - Hines with Oscar Peterson (Box 48)
    - Hines with Carl Pruitt (Box 48)
    - Hines with Pauline Rivelle (Box 48)
    - Hines with Red Saunders (Box 48)
    - Hines with Tony Scott (Box 48)
    - Hines with Arvell Shaw (Box 48)
    - Hines with Kay Starr (Box 48)
    - Hines with Buddy Tate (Box 48)
    - Hines with Clay Terry (Box 48)
    - Hines with Jack Teagarden (Box 48)
    - Hines with Sonny Thompson (Box 48)
    - Hines with Sinclair Traill (Box 48)
    - Hines with Sarah Vaughan (Box 48)
    - Hines with Dinah Washington (Box 48)
    - Hines with Harley White (Box 48)
    - Hines with Gerald Wilson (Box 48)
    - Hines with Teddy Wilson (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Louis Armstrong (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Count Basie (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Eubie Blake (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Teresa Brewer (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Les Brown (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Stanley Dance (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Sammy Davis Jr. (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Duke Ellington (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Dizzy Gillespie (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Phil Harris (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Janie Hines (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Claude Hopkins (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Marva Josie (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Marvin McRae (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Ranano Munolini (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Hughes Panassié (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Alex Racolin (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Gene Redd (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Lany Richardson (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Jimmy Rushing (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Red Sanders (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Arvell Shaw (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Victoria Spivey (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Joe Sullivan (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Buddy Tate (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Art Tatum (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Jack Teagarden (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Joe Williams (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Mayor Lionel Wilson (Box 48)
    - Hines with 2 or more, Trummy Wilson (Box 48)
    - Band Photos, Informal/Off Stage (Box 48)
    - Band Photos, Combos (6 & under) (Box 48)
    - Band Photos, Full Band (7 & over) (Box 48)
    - Grand Terrace, Artists appearing with Earl Hines and the Grand Terrace, 1928-1940 (Box 48)
  - Duke Ellington
    - Family Photographs (Box 49)
    - Early Years (Box 49)
    - 1930 (Box 49)
    - 1932 (Box 49)
    - 1933 (Box 49)
    - 1934 (Box 49)
    - 1935 (Box 49)
    - 1936 (Box 49)
    - 1937 (Box 49)
    - 1938 (Box 49)
    - 1939 (Box 49)
    - 1940 (Box 49)
    - 1942 (Box 49)
    - 1943 (Box 49)
    - 1944 (Box 49)
    - 1945 (Box 49)
    - 1946 (Box 49)
    - 1948 (Box 49)
    - 1950 (Box 49)
    - 1951 (Box 49)
    - 1953 (Box 49)
    - 1955 (Box 49)
    - 1956 (Box 49)
    - 1957 (Box 49)
    - 1958 (Box 49)
    - 1959 (Box 49)
    - 1960 (Box 49)
    - 1962 (Box 49)
    - 1963 (Box 49)
    - 1964 (Box 50)
    - 1965 (Box 50)
    - 1966 (Box 50)
    - 1967 (Box 50)
    - 1968 (Box 50)
    - 1969 (Box 50)
    - 1970 (Box 50)
    - 1971 (Box 50)
    - 1972 (Box 50)
    - 1973 (Box 50)
    - 1974 (Box 50)
    - Ellington with Cat Anderson (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Ivy Anderson (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Louis Armstrong (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Harold Ashby (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Alice Babs (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Leonard Bernstein (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Teresa Brewer (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Edward Brooks (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Lawrence Brown (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Harry Carney (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Diahann Carroll (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Stanley Dance (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Kay Davis (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Bea Ellis (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Joe Glaser (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Paul Gonsalves (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Sonny Greer (Box 51)
    - Ellington with J Grieson (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Freddy Guy (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Jimmy Hamilton (Box 51)
    - Ellington with W.C. Handy (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Skitch Henderson (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Woody Herman (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Johnny Hodges (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Geoffrey Holder (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Lyndon Johnson (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Money Johnson (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Taft Jordan (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Eartha Kitt (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Joe Lewis (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Marian Logan (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Wendell Marshall (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Fernanda Montel (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Richard Nixon (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Oscar Pettiford (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Otto Preminger (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Princess Margaret (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Russell Procope (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Queen Elizabeth (Box 51)
    - Ellington with John Sanders (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Romy Schneider (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Ernie Shepard (Box 51)
    - Ellington with George Simon (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Willie "The Lion" Smith (Box 51)
    - Ellington with James Stewart (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Billy Strayhorn (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Juan Tizol (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Irving Townsend (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Norris Turney (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Tony Watkins (Box 51)
    - Ellington with George Wein (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Tom Whaley (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Cootie Williams (Box 51)
    - Ellington with William B. Williams (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Booty Wood (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Sam Woodyard (Box 51)
    - Ellington with Rayburn Wright (Box 51)
    - Ellington-Band, 1920's (Box 52, Box 54)
      Oversized copy of 1929 band photopgraph found in Box 54.
    - Ellington-Band, 1930 (Box 52, Box 54)
      Oversized copy of 1930 band photograph found in Box 54.
    - Ellington-Band, 1932 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1933 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1934 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1935 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1936 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1937 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1938 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1939 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1940 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1941 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1943 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1945 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1946 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1948 (Box 52, Box 54)
      Additional oversized band photographs from 1948 found in Box 54.
    - Ellington-Band, 1950 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1952 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1955 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1956 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1958 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1959 (Box 52, Box 54)
      Additional oversized band photographs from 1959 found in Box 54.
    - Ellington-Band, 1960 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1961 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1962 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1963 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1964 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1966 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1965 (Box 52, Box 54)
      Additional oversized band photographs from 1965 found in Box 54.
    - Ellington-Band, 1968 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1969 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1970 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1971 (Box 52, Box 54)
      Additional oversized band photographs from 1971 found in Box 54.
    - Ellington-Band, 1973 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1974 (Box 52)
    - Ellington-Band, 1975 (Box 52)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Louis Armstrong (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Charlie Barnet (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Aaron Bell (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Louis Bellson (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Leonard Bernstein (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Bunny Briggs (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Nell Brookshire (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Benny Carter (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Ruth Ellington (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Bea Ellis (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Ella Fitzgerald (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Jimmy Hamilton (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Mort Herbert (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Woody Herman (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Earl Hines (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Johnny Hodges (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Lena Horne (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Quentin Jackson (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Rufus Jones (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Wendell Marshall (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Dean Martin (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Ray Nance (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Russell Procope (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Artie Shaw (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, James Stewart (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Rex Stewart (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Billy Strayhorn (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Tony Watkins (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Ben Webster (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Cootie Williams (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Mary Lou Williams (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Unidentified (Box 53)
    - Ellington-Band, Offstage (Box 53)
    - Cotton Club (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, Argentina (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, Bahamas (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, Brazil (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, Chile (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, Mexico (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, Peru (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, Uruguay (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, misc. (Box 53)
    - Latin American Tour 1968, NYC (Box 53)
    - Sacred Concert-Second, 1968 (Box 53)
    - Wisconsin, 1972 (Box 53)
    - Ellington-Exhibit, 1998 (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Sam Woodyard (Box 53)
    - Sacred Concert-1975 (Box 53)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, Harold Ashby (Box 53)
    - 1963 Far East Asia Tour (Box 53)
    - Ellington alone, oversize photos, 1955-1970 (Box 54)
    - Ellington with 2 or more, oversized photos (Box 54–55)
      One photograph with Billy Strayhorn and one other. The people found in the other photographs are not labeled.
    - Ellington-Band, oversized photos, 1929-1971 (Box 54)
  - Photo albums
    - Stanley Dance & His Olympus Camera Book I (Box 56)
      The first photo album, dated 1968, contains roughly 100 photographs taken by Stanley Dance. Several of the photos contain images of jazz performances from the Newport Jazz Festival and the 1968 Latin American tour. Also included are several offstage shots of jazz players such as Benny Carter, Joe Thomas, Count Basie, Ray Charles, and others.
    - Stanley Dance & His Olympus Camera Book II (Box 56)
      The second photo album contains roughly 100 photographs. Included are images from the Latin American tour, 1968, New Orleans, 1969, Newport 1969, New Orleans, 1970, and Earl Hines in San Francisco, 1969. Individuals found in the photos include Duke Ellington, Danny Barker, Tyree Glenn, Buddy Tate, Clark Terry, and others.
- Correspondence
  This series contains correspondence to and from Stanley and Helen Oakley Dance, with various jazz musicians, friends and family. Note that correspondence with Hugh Panassie and Madeleine Gautier (of the jazz organization Hot Club de France) can be found at the end of the alphabetical listing.
  Correspondence is organized alphabetically.
  - "A" (Box 59)
  - Ashcraft (Box 59)
  - Bailey-Bellson (Box 59)
  - Benjamin-Burns (Box 59)
  - Burnett, Robert W. (Box 59)
  - Callender-Chilton (Box 59)
  - Clark-Cullum (Box 59)
  - Dance Family Correspondence 1/2 (Box 60)
  - Dance Family Correspondence 2/2 (Box 60)
  - "Curt" (Box 60)
  - Daly-Driggs (Box 60)
  - Eldridge-Elliott (Box 61)
  - Fitzgerald-Francis (Box 61)
  - Feather, Leonard (Box 61)
  - Giddens-Greene (Box 61)
  - Hale-Hyman (Box 61)
  - "I" (Box 61)
  - Higgins, Jack L. (Box 61)
  - Jacquet-Jones (Box 62)
  - Ms. June Reed "Jayar" (Box 62)
  - Jovien, Harold (Box 62)
  - Keepnews-King (Box 62)
  - LaMour-Lowry (Box 62)
  - Love, Preston 1/3 (Box 62)
  - Love, Preston 2/3 (Box 62)
  - Love, Preston 3/3 (Box 62)
  - Maher-Murray (Box 63)
  - McGettisan, Beth (Box 63)
  - "N" (Box 63)
  - O'Brian-Otis (Box 63)
  - Panassié-Powell (Box 63)
  - Pocock, Gerald (Box 63)
  - P. Pescheux (HCF) 1/2 (Box 63)
  - P. Pescheux (HCF) 2/2 (Box 63)
  - "Q" (Box 63)
  - Ramey-Rushing (Box 63)
  - Schoenberg-Stowell (Box 64)
  - Tate-Thiele (Box 64)
  - Thompson-Traill (Box 64)
  - Varro-Voce (Box 64)
  - Warren-Woodyard (Box 64)
  - Williams, Martin (Box 64)
  - Y-Z (Box 64)
  - Unidentified Correspondence (Box 64)
  - Correspondence with Madeline Gautier and Hugh Panassié, 1934-1980 (Box 65)
- Materials related to Earl Hines
  Stanley Dance and Helen Oakley Dance collaborated with Earl Hines during the later years of his career. Stanley wrote a book entitled, "The World of Earl Hines", and Helen Oakley Dance ran HiCue records, a publishing company owned by Earl Hines and Johnny Hodges. The majority of material in this series comes from these projects.
  - News Clippings
    - 1940's (Box 66)
    - 1950's (Box 66)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 66)
    - 1964 (Box 66)
    - 1965 (Box 66)
    - 1966 (Box 66)
    - 1967 (Box 66)
    - 1968 (Box 66)
    - 1969 (Box 66)
    - 1970 (Box 66)
    - 1971 (Box 66)
    - 1972 (Box 66)
    - 1973 (Box 66)
    - 1974 (Box 66)
    - 1975 (Box 66)
    - 1976 (Box 66)
    - 1977 (Box 66)
    - 1978 (Box 66)
    - 1979 (Box 66)
    - 1970's (Box 66)
    - 1980 (Box 67)
    - 1981 (Box 67)
    - 1982 (Box 67)
    - 1983 (Box 67)
    - 1984 (Box 67)
    - 1986 (Box 67)
    - Undated (Box 67)
  - Programs and Publicity
    - 1950's (Box 67)
    - 1964 (Box 67)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 67)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 67)
    - 1971 (Box 67)
    - 1971-1974 (Box 67)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 67)
    - 1976 (Box 67)
    - 1978 (Box 67)
    - 1979 (Box 67)
    - 1980 (Box 67)
    - 1982 (Box 67)
    - 1984 (Box 67)
    - Undated, 1946 (Box 67)
  - Materials related to Earl Hines
    - Financial documents and tour related materials, 1958-1980 (Box 68)
      Contains handwritten financial notes, performance contracts, performance set lists, tour logistical documents, resumes from band musicians, documents from the 1966 tour to Russia, drafts of press releases and articles about Earl Hines, and licensing agreements with several recording and television companies.
    - Royalty statements, press quotes, article drafts, and other Hines related materials, 1981-1982 (Box 69)
      Contains contracts, concert set lists, cancelled checks, royalty statements, press statement quotes,drafts of articles written about Earl Hines, items from the "Hines Manual", photos from "The World of Earl Hines", photoshoot photos, works from the Hi Cue catalogue, and a proposal for an Earl Hines documentary.
    - "A Discography of Earl Hines 1923-1977" Compiled by Lionel Moxhet (Box 70)
    - Typescripts of Hi-Cue Catalogs, 1969-1970 (Box 70)
    - Writings about Earl Hines by Stanley Dance (Box 70)
    - Contracts (Box 70)
    - "How Gangsters Ran the Band Business" by Earl Hines (Box 70)
- Materials related to Duke Ellington
  Both Stanley Dance and Helen Oakley Dance worked closely with Duke Ellington. This series contains materials indicative of that relationship. Of particular interest is the collection of drafts and notes pertaining to "Music is My Mistress", Ellington's autobiography, which he prepared with Stanley Dance.
  - News clippings
    - 1933-1959 (Box 71)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 71)
    - 1963 (Box 71)
    - 1963 - Far East Tour (Box 71)
    - 1964 (Box 71)
    - 1965 (Box 71)
    - 1966 (Box 72)
    - 1967 (Box 72)
    - 1968 (Box 72)
    - 1968 - South America Tour (Box 72)
    - 1969 (Box 72)
    - 1969 - White House (Box 72)
    - 1970 (Box 72)
    - 1971 (Box 73)
    - 1972 (Box 73)
    - 1972 - University of Wisconsin Festival (Box 73)
    - 1973 (Box 73)
    - 1974 (Box 73)
    - 1975 (Box 73)
    - 1976 (Box 73)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 73)
    - 1977-1978 - Mercer Ellington Book (Box 73)
    - 1980 (Box 73)
    - 1981 (Box 73)
    - 1982 (Box 73)
    - 1984 (Box 73)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 74)
    - 1987 (Box 74)
    - 1988 (Box 74)
    - 1989 (Box 74)
    - 1990 (Box 74)
    - 1991 (Box 74)
    - 1992 (Box 74)
    - 1993 (Box 74)
    - 1994 (Box 74)
    - 1995 (Box 74)
    - 1996 (Box 74)
    - 1997 (Box 74)
    - 1998 (Box 74)
    - "World of Duke Ellington" Reviews (Box 74)
  - Programs
    - 1930's (Box 75)
    - 1940's (Box 55, Box 75)
      Oversized Irving Mills promotional brochure circa 1940 located in Box 55.
    - 1940's - Carnegie Programs (Box 75)
    - 1950's (Box 75)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 75)
    - 1963 (Box 75)
    - 1963 - Far East Tour (Box 75)
    - 1964 (Box 75)
    - 1965 (Box 75)
    - 1966 (Box 73)
    - 1967 (Box 75)
    - 1968 (Box 76)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 55)
  - Files
    - Radio transcripts, 1937-1946 (Box 77)
    - Script for "Man With Four Sides", 1955 (Box 77)
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1958-1959 (Box 77)
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1960-1962 (Box 77)
    - "The Ellington Tempo", 1962-1964 (Box 77)
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1963 (Box 77)
      Also includes concert set lists, memos, hand-written notes, and a Christmas card from Duke Ellington.
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1964 (Box 77)
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1965 (Box 77)
      Also includes concert set lists, record pricing information, and materials related to a Duke Ellington Sacred concert.
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1966 (Box 77)
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1967 (Box 77)
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1968 (Box 77)
      Also includes "Black, Brown, and Beige" transcript.
    - Materials from 1968 South American Tour (Box 77)
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1969 (Box 77)
      Also includes tour itineraries, concert set lists, and other notes.
    - Ellington Jazz Society materials, 1970 (Box 77)
      Also includes some publicity materials.
    - "Play On" script (Box 78)
    - "Queenie Pie" script with notes (Box 78)
    - Duke Ellington Sacred Concerts (Box 78)
    - "The Art is in the Cooking" by Duke Ellington (Box 78)
      Contains two drafts entitled "Conversations on Cape Cod" which precede the published article. Written in collaboration with Stanley Dance.
    - Duke Ellington eulogy and related correspondence (Box 78)
    - 1968 South America Tour (Box 78)
    - "The River" (Box 78)
    - Eulogies written by Duke Ellington (Box 78)
    - "Song of My Town" typescript (Box 78)
    - "Paris Blues" press reviews (Box 78)
    - Partial transcript of "Duke's Place" radio show, 1960 (Box 78)
    - Small articles written by Stanley Dance about Duke Ellington's activities, 1964-1966 (Box 78)
    - "Ailey Celebrates Ellington" (Box 78)
    - Duke Ellington notebook, 1927-1970 (Box 78)
      A notebook containing Duke Ellington quotes from various publications. Notes handwritten by Stanley Dance.
    - "Music is My Mistress" drafts, notes and correspondence (Box 79, Box 79A, Box 80)
      Includes typescripts of drafts, interviews, handwritten notes by Duke Ellington and by Stanley Dance. Some material is included in the published version of "Music is My Mistress". There is a substantial amount of material that does not appear in the book, but could have been intended for publication. This includes an interview with Sonny Greer, Q and A sessions (with Duke Ellington), Latin America tour notes from 1968, and various short essays.
    - Set lists from various performances from the Ellington Band, 1946-1972 (Box 80)
      Includes set lists from radio and television broadcasts.
    - Ellington band discography catalogues (Box 80)
      Includes extensive catalogues from Bluebird Records, Tempo Music Inc., and "The Ellington Chronicle" compiled by Joe Igo.
    - Appendix for unknown publication, Oct. 1933 (Box 80)
      Includes details on Ellington band personnel and Ellington's compositions.
    - Telegeneral radio transcripts, 1973-1976 (Box 80)
    - Drafts of publications about Duke Ellington by others (Box 81)
      Probably submitted to Stanley Dance for review.
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (Box 80)
      Contains fragments of drafts, itineraries, correspondence, some notes in Duke Ellington's hand and unidentified materials. ca. 50 pages. Also included is a signed photograph of Ella Logan.
- Sound Recordings, 1929-1998
  This series is currently being processed and digitized. It contains several hundred recordings on disc, reel-to-reel tape, and cassette tape. The series includes live shows, radio broadcasts, recording sessions, and a number of dubs. Musicians include Duke Ellington, Earl Hines, Louis Armstrong, Teddy Wilson, Count Basie, and many more.